more than 90% of the people who watch my
videos on YouTube are men now that's
weird because not about 80% of
psychology students are women so that is
not what you would expect right and so I
thought wow that's weird like what the
hell's going on here exactly and then
the other thing I've noticed is that
I've been talking a lot to the crowds
that I've been talking to not about
rights but about responsibility right
because you can't have the bloody
converse what are you doing you can't
have the conversation about rights
without the conversation about
responsibility because your rights are
my responsibility that's what they are
technically so you just can't have only
half of that discussion and we're only
having half that discussion the question
is well what the hell are you leaving
out if you only have that half of the
discussion and the answer is what you're
leaving out responsibility and then the
question is well what are you leaving
out if you're leaving out responsibility
and the answer might be well maybe
you're leaving out the meaning of life
that's what it looks like to me it's
like here you are suffering away what
makes it worthwhile
right you know you're completely oh
you're completely you have no idea what
you're you it's almost impossible to
describe how bad an idea that is
responsibility that's what gives life
meaning
it's like lift a load then you can
tolerate yourself right because look at
your useless easily hurt easily killed
why should you have any self-respect
that's the story of the fall pick
something up and carry it pick make it
heavy enough so that you can think yeah
well useless as I am at least I could
move that from there to there well
what's really cool about that is that
when I talk to these crowds about this
the man's eyes light up and that's very
quick I've seen that phenomena because
I've been talking about this
mythological material for a long time
and I can see when I'm watching crowds
people you know their eyebrows lift
their eyes let light out because I put
something together for them that's what
mythological stories do so I'm not
taking responsibility for that that's
what the stories do so I say the story
people go click click click you know in
their eyes light up
but this responsibility thing that's a
whole new order of this is that young
men are so hungry
for that it is unbelievable that's
another thing that we're doing to men
that's a very bad idea and to boys it's
like you're pathological and oppressive
it's like fine then why the hell am I
going to play that's that if that's the
situation if I get no credit for bearing
responsibility it could bloody well be
sure I'm not going to bear any but then
you know your life is useless and
meaningless and you have you're not
you're full of self-contempt and
nihilism and and that's not good and so
that's why I think all right that's what
I think's going on at a deeper level
with regards to men needing this
direction a man has to decide that he's
going to do something he has to decide
that
yeah well you know partly what you're
trying to do in the future authoring
processes say okay well what's your
highest value right it's the star it's
like okay what are you aiming for you
can decide man but you know there's some
criteria it should be good for you it
should be good for you in a way that
facilitates your moving forward maybe it
should be good for you in a way that's
also good for the family in the
community it should cover the the domain
of life I mean there's constraints on
what you should regard as a value but
you but within those constraints you
have the choice you have choice well the
thing is is that people will carry a
heavy load if they get to pick the
goddamn load so and they think well I
won't carry any load it's like okay fine
but then you're like the sled dog that
doesn't have a sled to pull you're just
gonna you're gonna tear pieces out of
your own legs because you're bored you
know you need people are pack animals
they need they need to pull against a
weight and and that's not true for
everyone it's not true particularly say
for low conscientious people I mean
maybe they're open and creative or
extroverted and some other things but
for the for the typical person they
they'll eat themselves they'll eat
themselves up unless they have a load
this is why there's such an opiate
epidemic among dispossessed white
middle-aged guys who are unemployed in
the u.s. it's like they lose their job
they're done right they despise
themselves they develop chronic pain
syndromes and depression and the chronic
pain is treated with opiates it's like
that's what we're doing so yeah that's
what it looks like to me is you you have
to and it's so interesting to watch the
young man when you talk to them about
responsibility there's a god damn
thrilled about it it just blows me away
it's like really that's what's that's
the counterculture grow the hell up and
do something useful really I could do
that oh I'm so excited by that idea no
one ever mentioned that before
it's like rights rights rights rights
Jesus it's it's it's appalling it's it's
and and I feel that that's deeply felt
by the people who are who are coming out
to to listen to these sorts of things -
they're they've had enough of that so
and they better have because it
it's a non-productive mode of being
responsibility man that's where the
meaning in life is so all right good one
more class they will see you next week